<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.mc.gdk.launcher</id>
  <name>Minecraft GDK Launcher</name>
  <summary>Minecraft Bedrock (GDK) launcher for Linux</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Modern GTK4 / Libadwaita launcher to run Minecraft Bedrock (GDK) on Linux
      using GDK-Proton. Includes ProxyPass integration for Microsoft login and
      custom server routing, plus an integrated setup wizard.
    </p>
    <p>
      Oyun dosyaları dahil değildir; Minecraft Bedrock Windows sürümünü
      (Minecraft.Windows.exe) kendiniz sağlamalısınız.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.mc.gdk.launcher.desktop</launchable>
  <developer_name>mercimekcik</developer_name>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/mdevlopm/mc-gdk-launcher-gui</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/mdevlopm/mc-gdk-launcher-gui/issues</url>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>
  <releases>
    <release version="3.1" date="2026-06-27">
      <description>
        <p>GDK Launcher version 3.1. Major security and stability audit release.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added SHA-256 integrity verification for all downloaded dependencies (MiTM protection).</li>
          <li>Improved Microsoft GameInput MSI extraction to use pure Python (no msiexec hangs).</li>
          <li>Fixed Flatpak environment paths and improved Proton/Wine memory offset patching for UWP support.</li>
          <li>Added atomic writes for config files to prevent data loss.</li>
          <li>Enhanced Wayland compatibility and dynamic VKD3D workarounds for AMD GPUs.</li>
          <li>Added GUI-based dependency error alerts.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.0" date="2026-06-26">
      <description>
        <p>GDK Launcher version 3.0. Stability improvements for the ProxyPass integration, fixes for game startup failure/hangs, and final general stability issues resolved. The launcher is now fully stable and ready for general use.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.4.5" date="2026-06-23">
      <description>
        <p>GDK Launcher version 2.4.5 final hotfix. Fixes the Flatpak bwrap mount and ldconfig 256 errors by ensuring correct directory paths exist prior to linking.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
